+91 9035090297

manali.raj0@gmail.com

HR CONSULTING & SALES

Multi-specialty professional endeavoring a stable & challenging position as an HR and Sales Manager in growth-oriented industry having 5 year of experience, where my expertise & experience will significantly add to overall prosperity of the company and render the opportunities to my career.

Key Skills

- Record Management
- Employee & Labor relation
- Sales Programs & Techniques
- New Business Development
- Strategic planning
- Talent onboarding

- Performance Management
- Public Speaking
- Business & Growth Planning
- Product Adoption
- Vendor Engagement
- Client Relationship

Professional History

LifeTech scientific India Pvt Ltd Sr. Territory Manager

Designated to be among first Territory Managers –HR admin ever in organization, after demonstrating consistently outstanding sales success offering and individual clinical practice growth.

- **4** Successfully assisted in union negotiations ending in signed contracts
- Requested staffing needs from department managers to avoid under-staffing
- Recommended appropriate training for new hires
- Recruited and identified promising candidates
- Recommended out-sourcing when required
- Negotiated favorable rates with staffing agencies
- Insured all required employment documents were completed and signed
- **♣** Administered the benefits program for all employees
- **♣** First one to get success in many new products implants
- Exceeded individual quota every year
- Selected to speak at national corporate sales meetings to provide training on new products
- First, one to get approval for different new products in government as well as non-government hospital elevated provider from 0 to top 8% status in 5 months

2013-2015

Multimedics 2012-2013

Territory Manager

Conducted sales and marketing of cardiac implants to interventional cardiologists and cardiac surgeons, with privileges at major hospitals and medical centers. Trained and educated physicians on instrumentation and supported surgeons with product implementation during surgery in the lab.

- Increased overall revenue approximately 35%
- Conducted lots of CME's and educational camps

Advance Therapeutics Ltd. Territory Manager

2011 - 2012

Recruited to manage a portfolio of medical testing solutions, expand revenue from existing accounts, and close new prospects. Employed consultative sales approach, educating primary care physicians on new technologies.

- Integrally contributed to 40% overall business expansion
- ♣ Ranked in top 20% of 500 specialists nationally
- Named Employee of the Year

Integrated Disease Management Account Manager

2010 - 2011

Advanced to managing role directing sales team of 10 product sales specialists, and held senior responsibility for recruitment, assignments, including performance management. identifying retailers, acquiring new accounts, customizing incentives and providing training and education.

Ranked as #1 sales specialist team nationwide for that year

Education

Qualification	Specialization	% Aggregate
MBA	HR & Marketing	75 %
Master in Science	Nutrition	80%
Bachelor in Science	Clinical Nutrition and Dietetics	82%